Elisabeth C Gray

elcgray@gmail.com 317-435-1257 http://elisabethgray.me/cv

Curriculum Vitae

Profile

My work experience over the past ten years is based in technology–from service to education to financial tech roles–but my long-term focus is on people, improving civic engagement and political transparency. Academically, I focused my research on media technology's role in conflict, primarily in the MENA and the Balkans. The underlying theme in my work is hinged upon one observation: the tools we use to disseminate information expose base commonalities in our motivations for conflict and peace.

Research Interests

- Relationships between technology, society, and conflict
- Role of media in conflict, particularly in:
 - o Bosnia-Herzegovina
 - Middle East North Africa (MENA)
 - United States-particularly with regard to racial inequality

Papers

- Never Again? The US Response to Genocide in Bosnia and Rwanda
- Building Fences: Saudi Arabia's Strategy for National Security
- Information Warfare: The Roles of Social Media in Conflict
- Se Va a Poner Feo: The Culture of Violence in Mexico and Its Impact on Development Efforts

Projects and Presentations

Title	Year	Description
Documentation Domination: How to Build a Knowledge Sharing Culture in 4 Easy Steps	2015	 One of 10 proposals selected by Atlassian panel for the <i>Interact</i> track Full house for the presentation, with over 100 people turned away

Social Media and the Arab Uprisings	2015	 Built website using Jekyll to host blog posts on Github Designed and implemented a structured research plan Composed and delivered 14 articles on the topic in blog post format Performed a formative evaluation of the project data (Twitter, Facebook, and Google analytics)
Israel-Palestine Project	2014	 Led a team of four through a half-semester group project which explored options for conflict resolution in the region of Israel-Palestine Managed and contributed to the composition of a paper and presentation on the subject
Out of Sight	2005	 Researched homeless outreach programs available in Indianapolis Interviewed outreach professionals as well as individuals experiencing homelessness Collected, edited, and archived audio and video from interviews Presented undergraduate capstone—a video documentary on homeless youth in Indianapolis, Indiana—to a lecture hall of faculty and peers Facilitated a viewing and question-and-answer session on the research, production, and findings of the project Defended research, production, and findings before a faculty panel

Education

University	Degree	Graduation Year
Arizona State University	Master of Science, Global Technology and Development	2015
Indiana University Purdue University Indianapolis, School of Informatics	 Bachelor of Science, Media Arts and Sciences Concentration, Journalism Minor, French Computer Science certificate coursework 	2005

Competencies

Computer Science

Skill	Related Tools and Packages	Experience 1=novice 3=advanced
Apple OS	Mac OS Terminal	3
BibTeX	Jekyll-Scholar	3
HTML	Google Web Tools, Atom	3
Markdown	Atom	3
CSS	Google Web Tools, Atom	2
Git	Github	2
JavaScript	Node.js, NPM	2
Ruby	Jekyll, Liquid	2
Windows	Command Prompt	2
Apple iOS	Xcode	1
Continuous integration	Travis CI	1
Data analysis and visualization	IBM SPSS, Google Analytics, Twitter Analytics, TweetTracker	1
SQL	Sequel Pro	1

Communication

Skill	Related Tools and Packages	Experience 1=novice 3=advanced
Digital publishing	iWork, Microsoft Word, Adobe: InDesign, Pagemaker	3
English	-	3
Knowledge management	Atlassian Confluence, PBworks, MediaWiki	3
Project management	Trello, Github, Asana, Desk	3
Research	LexisNexis, JSTOR, Google Scholar, Open Access Journals	3
Technical writing	Atom, Google Docs, Github	3
Video editing	Final Cut Pro	3

Customer relationship management	Salesforce, <u>desk.com</u>	2
Database management	Microsoft Excel, FileMaker Pro	2
Digital media creation	iLife, Adobe: Acrobat, Illustrator, Photoshop	2
Educational assessment	NWEA MAP testing	2
French	-	2
Student information administration	PowerSchool	2

Work Experience

Braintree

Title	Years	Job Description				
	2013-present					 Founded a dedicated documentation team in the creation and maintenance of internal product, process, and procedural content in <u>Confluence</u>, <u>support articles</u>, and <u>API documentation</u>
			 Design and implement methods for syncing shared content between separate organizations 			
Knowledge Management Lead / Ops Specialist Chicago, IL		 Collaborate with cross-organizational teams on technical initiatives to improve documentation content, accessibility, and functionality 				
		 Interact with Product and Operations teams to determine new product documentation needs 				
		 Coordinate with Braintree help desk team on Confluence version upgrade timelines, creating user permission groups, and setting space permissions 				
		Collaborated with a lead developer to create a company wiki				
		 Managed Operations content and process development for the first joint product release as a subsidiary of PayPal 				

Integration Support Specialist Chicago, IL	2011-2013	 Supported business owners and developers with gateway integration questions and issues
		 Wrote articles detailing internal policies and procedures as well as public-facing support articles to assist merchants with common questions
		 Managed bank-specific article composition project
		 Trained new company employees on products, policies, and procedures
		 Built computer image for new hire computers and provided company-wide technical support prior to the establishment of a dedicated IT team

University of Chicago Charter School

Title	Years	Job Description	
		Organized and facilitated a 1:1 laptop program for 600 students	
		 Built and managed maintenance of two static computer labs and 12+ mobile computer and iPad carts 	
		Assisted in server maintenance	
	2008-2011	Developed policy and procedure for student and staff technology use	
			 Designed and administered training sessions for both teachers and students
Technology Director		 Reconciled a technology budget of up to \$500,0000 	
Chicago, IL		• Reduced the technology loss rate on campus from 36% to 3.69% by 2009 and to 0.71% by 2011	
		Managed technology asset maintenance and distribution	
		 Developed technology inventory database using Filemaker; system was adopted across three other campuses 	
		 Provided technical support for computer-based assessments such as the NWEA MAP tests 	
		Repaired and replaced faulty and/or obsolete technology	
		 Deployed Apple MacBooks, MacBook Pros, iMacs, and iPads 	

Apple Inc.

Title	Years	Job Description
Mac Genius Chicago, IL		Diagnosed and repaired computer hardware and software issues
	2006-2008	Educated customers on computer maintenance and troubleshooting
		Trained new employees
Mac Visual Specialist Indianapolis, IN	2004-2006	 Managed software versions and hardware upgrades for front and back of house operations

Gold Wing Touring Association

Title	Years	Job Description	
Media and Marketing Manager	2003-2004	 Designed, organized, and edited the non-profit association's monthly magazine Negotiated and communicated with advertisers and printers 	
Indianapolis, IN		 Developed marketing, advertising plans, and media for the association 	

Professional Development

Course	Organization	Year	Status
Jekyll and Github Pages	Udemy	2015	Complete
Management Fundamentals	American Management Association	2015	Complete
SQL	Udemy	2015	Complete
Big Data and Social Physics	edX	2015	In progress
Javascript	Udemy	2015	In progress

${\bf Memberships}$

Title	Organization	Years
Member	Association for Information Science and Technology	2015
Technology Committee	Woodlawn Children's Promise Community Chicago, IL	2009-2011
Technology Educator	Illinois Computing Educators Chicago, IL	2009-2011

Conferences and Events

- Atlassian Summit (2015)
- Write the Docs (2015)
- Chicago Humanities Festival
 - o Hacker, Hoaxer, Whistleblower, Spy with Gabriella Coleman (2015)
 - o Dispatches from Dystopia with Kate Brown (2015)
 - Media Against Fascism: From World War II to the Psychedelic Sixties with Fred Turner (2015)
 - o The New Face of Global Activism with Maryam Al-Khawaja (2014)
- PowerSchool University (2010)
- <u>Illinois Computing Educators</u> (2009-2010)

Certifications

- Apple Certified Support Professional (ACSP) 10.5
- Mac OS X Support Essentials v10.5 Certification
- Apple Certified Mac Technician 10.5 (ACMT)